Harrison A Latimer

hlatimer266@gmail.com

Product Engineer

OBJECTIVE: To engage and solve unique problems associated with the manufacturing of complex products and to improve over all quality.

PROFILE: An engineer focused on excelling in manufacturing and design. Below are listed given character strengths:

- Critical thinker
- Motivator in team settings
- Clear and concise communicator
- Excellent judgment skills in high pressure situations
- Self-motivated to complete tasks ahead of schedule

EMPLOYMENT

December 2013 – Present (3 Year & 5 Months) Oregon Physics LLC

Hillsboro, Oregon

- **Product Engineer**
 - Assist Oregon Physics scientists in the mechanical design of new and existing products
 - Assembly of Ion/Electron sources and their associated control electronics.
 - Manage manufacturing projects from purchase to final test
 - Generation of work instructions for lon/electron sources and control electronics
 - Test sources and control electronics to meet customer's required specifications
 - Experience with Oscilloscopes, DC power supplies, and function generators for electronics test
 - Experience with small vacuum systems and basic understand of electronics / mechanical design
 - Design components using Soildworks 3D CAD software
 - Create automated test software in Python
 - Work with SEM & FIB in small capacity

June 2013 – December 2013 (6 months)

Coherent inc.

Wilsonville, Oregon

Manufacturing Engineer (Contingent)

- Assist and develop quality control and preventative maintenance procedures
- Develop training procedure for new product introduction (laser remotes)
- Training and support of technicians for manufacturing
- Experience in clean room facilities
- Improvement of current manufacturing techniques (Vacuum chambers)
- Laser assembly construction and implementation with Coherent products
- Electronics and Vacuum chamber data analysis
- Support for co works and customers on RoHS/REACH declarations
- Experience with Agile as it relates to manufacturing and greening procedures (ECO's, MCO's, etc)

May 2012 – August 2012 Rowan University Glassboro, New Jersey

Material Science Research Assistant

- Experience with low pressure vacuum chamber deposition
- Deposition of Sapphire via magnetron sputtering
- Experience with both Rf and DC pulse current controllers
- Data analysis with WDXRF machinery
- Work with X-ray diffraction machinery and data analysis
- Experience with scanning electron microscope and software

EDUCATION

2008-2013 Rowan University Glassboro,

New Jersey **BS**, **Physics**

2017-2019 Oregon State University Corvallis,

Oregon

Post-Bacc., Computer Science (online)

ACADEMIC HIGHLIGHTS

<u>Physics:</u> Modern physics (intro to quantum mech.), Optics, Optical research, Material science research, Introduction to lens design in ZEMAX, Electricity and Magnetism I, Quantum Mechanics I, Statistical Physics

<u>Mathematics:</u> Differential Equations, Differential Calculus, Integral Calculus, Vector Calculus, Linear Algebra, Fourier analysis

Chemistry: Organic chemistry I & II, Organic chemistry research

SOFTWARE / CODINGSKILLS

• SolidWorks, MS Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Visual basic, C, Python, and GitHub

References:

Available upon request.